hello everybody you're here you know why
you're here you're here because of this
here because of luminize Kayla's there
she wants some food um in this video I
am going to give you my honest opinion
on the new brand luminize from Arcadia
and what I think of the product I've had
it now for 3 months and I'm going to
give you a 100% honest review of the
product straight off the bat I love The
Branding I generally do I think it
really sticks out I think the Box is
very Sleek I think it's great that they
have all this detail on the back I
generally really like that some thoughts
gone into it um you know it's it is a
nice box I genuinely really do think it
stands out it's quite sleek and some
people aren't going to care I do care I
think it looks kind of Cool Sup K the
new units are a little bit deeper but
most of us like these black enclosures
so it's nice and Sleek you know it
Blends
in really well into the enclos eroses
they're nice and Sleek I've had no
issues as regarding to spraying due to
the new ip65 connection on both units so
I've had no issue one downside that I
know people are going to say is the new
connectors are not the same as the old
connectors so you have to bring the vivs
out get the new connectors in it is a
little bit of a faf if you've just got
one or two reptiles and it's easy to get
to whereas these ones here I can get
behind them whereas these ones here I
can't so I have to pull stuff out and
it's it is a fth but it's worth it and
it is worth it because of what luminize
can
do conventionally most of us have
reptiles just on and off and what do I
mean by
that there you go they're off and when
they come back on in the
morning there you go they're on which is
mad whereas now with luminize Kermit
gets a ramp up and a ramp down so I can
change his daylight hours I can can make
them longer I can make them shorter I
can make it brighter for longer I can
make it like a long drawn out Sunrise if
I really want I have so much flexibility
yes fine with the hallogen I have to
have a Wi-Fi plug so I can program when
not to come on that's fine cuz that can
come on first thing in the morning and
then I have so I have the hallogen to
come on first thing in the morning then
I have the LED to start ramping up then
I have the UVB on I only have the UV on
for about 60 for about 6 hours of the
day so the UV is only on through the
midst of the day and then the UV dims
off and then the hallogen dims off and
I've been playing around with it and
seeing what works for him and you know
it's I had Clips in the other video I'll
add some b-roll into this but it's
really cool to walk into your room and
just see like the sunrise or the sunset
and see the enclosure like looking
ominously like the light drifting away
or drifting up it it generally makes me
feel worse and like bad for all my other
reptiles and Kermit's Behavior
has changed he his Cadian rhythm is
getting a lot better he tends to come
out later in the morning rather than
just like he doesn't normally when all
the lights come on he comes out whereas
now he's not really coming out until the
LED start to get a bit brighter as they
start to dim down he takes himself off
the bed he's not caught out by the
timing most of our reptiles take
themselves off the bed they learn this
whereas with now lumiz he's learning it
more so so colors I never really saw his
true color potential until now
underneath luminize and I'm not I'm not
just saying it I have I'll add a b-roll
video but it is so mindblowing how
everyone here knows that I love LEDs if
you watch me I'm really into my LEDs the
colors on this lizard under this
lighting is like nothing I've ever seen
another massive massive massive thing
that I'm glad that they've done is
they've changed the way that the t5s
clip in so it's no longer a Twist system
it's a push and then plug in clip so no
I've had a few T5 units break where I've
tried to twist the lamps and then little
pins at the end have broken off I've had
that happen many of times I'm sure
you've all had that happen it's changed
also the jungle Dawn is brighter what I
know and the UVB but the jungle Dawn is
brighter I have just the jungle Dawn
here this is the new shiny fancy Lumin
eyes I've been raising this m lizard and
some baby Gillan on it and then I have
the same two of the mystery lizard just
under a normal jungle Dawn and this one
comes out more and basks more is it the
lizard is it the lighting who knows the
Gillan ey that are in here they sit
under the light here on this Branch they
also have other branches they can sit on
whereas the Gill and I I'm raising in
here there was a jungle dwn but I'll be
honest it broke um an old style one they
have the same opportunities and they sit
under the H hallogen more than they
would the LEDs now does that mean that
they
prefer the does that mean they prefer
the luminize or does that mean they just
are utilizing different opportunities I
don't speak lizard but these two
enclosures it's hard to pick up but I
have checked it under my Lux meter are
brighter than those two
enclosures these two are incredibly
clean and Incredibly bright the app
enables you to set scenes you can have
up to 50 devices on the app you can set
scenes you can pick motions you can go
through and I've got Kermit LED Kermit
UVB all on a completely different time
schedule you can set it up you can play
around with it I have the babies over
there just on a separate time schedule
and you can play around with them so
when it comes to winter time I can set a
schedule
for Indonesian winter or Australian
winter and then everybody can go on the
Indonesian winter or the Australian
winter depending on what part of the
world they're from and I can just go
right clock is starting to go back ramp
down ramp down ramp down ramp down for
me personally in my keeping seasonality
and seasoning animals I test to a lot of
My Success in breeding also as well when
setting scenes remember to start it with
0% and end it with 0% as you can see me
doing on the screen here because if you
don't the light is going to be running
at a low capacity through the night and
obviously you don't want that so
remember when you do your scenes start
it at zero end it at zero you don't have
to have the 50% that I do you can just
have it for example come on at 8:00 a.m.
ramp up to 100% so 8:00 a.m. 0% you go
then to 12 p.m. so 12:00 a.m. whatever
midday is so from 8 till 12 it will ramp
up 100% And then 12 till 6 it's at 100%
And then 6 till 10 it ramps down to 0%
I'm pretty much changing my entire room
over to luminize I
when I can afford to do so as of this
video I don't know the price bracket I'm
going to not sit here and again front if
it's silly cly City money and when I say
silly money hundreds of pounds I'm still
going to get it but it's going to be a
lot slower I genuinely believe it's
worth the money I've seen massive change
in Kermit but I can't tell how much it
is I would love to but I don't know but
I will be changing especially things
like my toad heads you know and my
Gillan I where at the moment they're
currently in a seat I have 1 2 3 4 four
I have five separate lamps in with my G
and I which are five separate lamps I
need to control I can now just change
over to this have three separate lamps
sorry if you can hear kada she thinks
she's getting
fed bloody
lizard but yeah my Gillan I I'm in the
process of I'm in the process of
wintering my Gillan I so I'm changing
the daylight hours I'm mixing things up
with luminize one the light is brighter
two I'm saving money because it's not
just on and off for 6 hours it ramps up
and then ramps down and I'm saving
energy and then I could just go you know
what I I don't want the UVB I want the
UVB on to be on for an hour I haven't
have I haven't got to have multiple
timers and Chang multiple things it's
all just done in app like inh house done
and I've even been tempted like oh get a
little iPad and I can just keep it in
the reptile room and I'm like all right
that's it all the schedules and nerding
out about it it it is good and again I'm
not going to sit here and lie Arcadia
have not told me to say anything I've
spoken to Arcadia and they said look if
you don't want to make a video don't
make a video if you don't like it then
please tell us first but say that you
don't like it they have been true to me
by enabling me to be true to myself I
haven't had any hiccups with it I had
one instance where the LED wasn't quite
on properly and I went in the app just
clicked um what button was it save
schedule and it reset itself and it was
completely fine and even then I don't
think I had to set it up I had it set up
properly in the first place so I think
that was a me error not a product error
but other than that I've had no issues
and again to be completely honest when
it's like this it's midday both lamps
are on at 100% capacity you kind of
forget yourself but when you walk in and
the lights all dimmed down and it's
gloomy and it's starting to come and you
think oh my God like that is sick I
remember how excited I was when John
spoke to me about this and he said like
oh this is the plan this is what we're
bringing out this is what we're doing
and I remember thinking to myself I was
like this is going to be incredible
obviously I hadn't seen it I hadn't had
an idea I didn't know what was going on
I just had the idea I hadn't had the
idea had the idea I had the idea in my
head what it was going to be but it was
just over a phone call so I didn't quite
physically know what it was going to be
and when I received it and set it all up
and played plugged and played around
with it generally the first thing I was
like I need this for everybody and we're
3 months in now and I still want this
for everybody and it's been so hard not
to tell people I've had a few friends
like by newer um UVB or jungle Dawns and
I'm like oh my God I can't tell anybody
and I think out of the whole thing that
was the worst bit for me this is I
honestly believe it's going to change
reptile keeping and I'm not just saying
that if you think about it like first
thing in the morning someone just shines
a phone torch in your eyes or just draws
like you're like oh my God this is what
our reptiles have whereas Kermit now he
just living his life he is so attuned to
his enclosure now like his timing his
bedtime his routine he has days and I
can slowly ramp things down so he has
less daylight hours and I'm hoping that
I remember to add some Boll which I am
going to do but seeing the enclosure
like brighten up in the morning or dim
down at
night it is really something to behold
it I can't you can't fathom it I can't
explain it because it sounds the most
simple thing because we have that as a
species whereas our animals and boxes
are
just this changes it it changes the game
it it really does and it's so much
brighter it's a cleaner cleaner light
like a lot cleaner of a light so again I
will be changing over I've got some I
was planning on buying a new lizard but
I've decided not to and I'm going to buy
some more lumiz when it's officially out
in a few days after making this video
it's even simple stuff like this my
gecko enclosure I don't have them on as
long as my other animals I have to have
a separate time and a I could just have
aluminized UVB in here instead of just a
normal UVB in here and I could just have
it to ramp up ramp down and give my
geckos a decent season same as mango
like again she has the UVB here and the
Hallens and different LEDs and different
lights oh that's that's another thing I
should probably check this but the UVB
the led the LED comes in like a 6 foot
length maybe like a like an 80 wat like
a massive massive massively bright LED
I've also seen Kermit like flaring his
ribs out towards light when when he um
it was basing which I've never really
seen him do before even now look at like
seeing his Blues the camera obviously is
not doing him
Justice the colors and this isn't even
directly under the light the colors on
this
lizard like look he is
glowing and I mean people are going to
look at like oh yeah we get to save
money and we get to save energy a b your
lizards are or reptiles your reptiles
your amphibians your pets they're going
to start to be able to live how they
would expect to live you know we're all
on about this whole oh keep him wild you
know keep them close to Nature and I
said on my podcast before like oh where
do we draw the line we keep them close
to AG but we're handling keep you know
the on off that we all take for granted
of lights and I know some people stagger
them but if you stagger your for example
hallogen comes on great then the LED
comes on great but the LED just comes on
so it's still an instant like you know
whereas
this some of my enclosures are set up
like this one's set up to have different
Bobs come on at different times but when
those LED bars come on they just come on
and I can't avoid that it's the dimming
of the UVB as well though like dimming
an LED it's not I'm an electrician we
dim LEDs at work all the goddamn time
whereas now the UVB dims and it works
well it's not flickery it's not juty
when you film it it doesn't like mango
stupid cheap LEDs that whereas this
clean I'm going to do a completely
separate video um on utilizing the app
I'm going to make that just a dedicated
short video which I haven't done yet as
you can probably all tell from this
video how spotty I am and my bags your
boys had things going on but I really
wanted to get this video out and I am
filming this 3 days before the release
anyway my honest opinion is I love it I
genuinely love it the wild Recreation
that obviously we all know that John
goes on about I need to feed ker in a
minute I'll put the clip at the end of
the video for the people that are still
here he I've been getting to know him
over the
last six months and the man is
incredibly incredibly incredibly
passionate about the world Recreation
for our captive reptiles and amphibians
and her tailes and pets and birds and
whatever
um this is in my opinion gamechanging
this is great every time I walk into my
room and the light is dimmed it blows my
brain and the changes I have seen in K
Kermit are worth it they are worth
buying it for me to Warrant buying it
he's already starting to look to go to
bed and the lights are going off in a
few hours he understands time a lot
better now than he ever has his colors
are cleaner his activity levels during
midday full lighting is more than it's
ever been it really excites me to get
all my animals switched over to this and
again I don't know the price I'm not
going to sit here and be like yeah I'm
going to do it I am going to invest in a
couple straight away I already have the
LED over there I'm going to buy a UVB I
have the LED and the UVB in here then I
have an LED over there and I'm going to
first thing I'm going to buy is a UVB
for that so I'm instantly straight away
everything here has UVB and LEDs you
know that with me but I will be changing
every new bul from here on out will be
luminize and for enclosures that I can
afford to do so I'll be changing I will
be doing separate small videos on just
the little bits and Nuance that I found
with using it but for the most part you
will not regret it honestly please trust
me I'm not paid to say this at all I
genuinely believe in Arcadia as a brand
every single light in this room is
Arcadia as regards to like my UVB 80% of
my my LEDs or
Arcadia um all of them bar the free
lumiz I brought with my own money I've
never been given stuff like people like
oh okay come on come on now you know me
I'm truthful I'm honest I genuinely
genuinely believe believe in this I
think it is going to revolutionize the
reptile keeping industry I know a lot of
fish people have been like oh it's about
time doesn't matter how long it took
we're here now and we have it luminize
the brand new brand from Arcadia
get on board I've been I've just been
thinking did I say that it saves you 30%
energy it saves you 30%
energy it was worth sticking around to
the end of the video if you ask
me we're just going to let it run
patreon your that
way hey
kayada you going back in
then that's the video done thanks for
tuning in like comment subscribe
by
that